hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
starting with this session we'll be
going through a number of different test
automation obstacles which are part of
this obstacle course uh web page which
is defined by try centers
now there are different obstacles which
have been defined here which test your
knowledge on different parts of Tosca
this is a very good starting point if
you want to test what you have learned
until now in Tosca and where do you
think you lack knowledge so that you can
focus on those particular things within
Tosca
now I'm going to take you through all
the different obstacles which are
present in this particular obstacle
course and we'll go through each of the
test automation challenges which you
will face in your real-time applications
as well so I will tell you how you can
solve this obstacles the best possible
way using the different features of
Tosca which is available
so let's start with the first test
automation obstacle which is named as
IDs are not everything now as part of
this obstacle we need to click on this
click me button okay so seems pretty
simple but
um let's scan this module and then we
will see what is the actual challenge in
clicking on this button
so let me open Tosca here and then I'm
going to scan this particular module
here
okay so I'm going to select the
application here and click on scan now
and then I'm going to go to the advanced
tab
okay so here we can see there are the
two links don't and click me right now
let's see uh if we select this click me
um
Tosca is telling us that this particular
item is not unique okay
and the reason is using this ID and tag
for this particular element it is not
able to identify that uniquely okay now
if you look at this don't link okay
uh the ID and tag are exactly the same
so these two are basically uh two
similar controls two similar links which
have got the same ID and obviously they
are links so they will have the same tag
right so the whole idea behind this
obstacle is that you should not always
stick to the ID property okay whenever
you have uh controls which have got
similar properties you should try to use
different properties other than ID okay
so you should also try to use a
combination of different technical
properties through which you can easily
identify this any control uniquely okay
so in this case you can see the ID and
tag is not enough here right so what
else we can use
now if you look at both these controls
you will see that the inner text right
is different for both these controls so
that could be a good starting point so
we can look to use the inner text here
and once we select the inner text in the
technical property you will see that now
this item is unique so that solves most
part of the challenge because clicking
on the link won't be difficult once
you're able to identify it uniquely so
let's go ahead and save this now
and let's close this
now we will use this to basically
create a test case okay
so I will just rename this module here
okay and then I'm going to create a test
case folder here called obstacles
inside this I'm going to create my first
obstacle
I'll just name this with the particular
obstacle number so that I can identify
it later
and then I'm going to drag this module
here okay
and the simple thing which we need to do
here is to click on it here as you know
we can use the click option but as per
the best practice you should also look
to not use this click method which is a
mouse uh keyboard method right which is
a slower in performance also it is not
recommended by press centers right so
we'll be using the other option which is
the X okay it does the same thing it
clicks on the particular link and then
following the best practices I am going
to name this click link
okay so I am going to rename my test
step so that I know what is going on
here right
so that's my test case and then I'm
going to complete or change the
workstate to completed
so now I'm going to run this particular
test case so let's go ahead and run it
in scratchbook
and now it should be clicking on the
click mail link or button
okay so as you can see uh Tosca was able
to identify that control and click on it
and then the obstacle was completed
by all means this was a very easy
obstacle to start off with but it is a
very common scenario which you will face
while doing automation on any web
application you will come across
different controls which have got same
properties and then you need to fall
back on different properties or you also
need to try different identification
mechanisms in order to identify these
controls which are not unique on the
application
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video